Alex Weber Front-End Developer

Languages: Mandarin

alexaaron.weber@gmail.com | +1 (248) 790 8803 | Pleasant Ridge, MI <u>Linkedin.com/in/alex-a-weber/</u> | <u>GitHub.com/AlexAaronWeber</u>

SUMMARY

I am a student of languages with a professional background in education with a focus in teaching English. After graduating university, I lived in Wuhan, China for two years where I studied Mandarin, Chinese. The COVID-19 pandemic has led to an opportunity for me to devote time to an interest I have always wanted to explore deeper - software development. During my studies of programming, I was able to use my passion for learning languages to come to a deep understanding of development tools such as HTML5, CSS, Javascript, and Angular.js. While I expand on these skills and learn more about software development, I would love to use my current knowledge to explore creating fun, personal projects and work as a front-end developer.

EDUCATION

Grand Circus Front-end Bootcamp, Detroit, Michigan

July 2020 - September 2020

Projects include: Scrum's Pets (JS, HTML5, CSS) Cinéma (Angular, Web API) WellBeing (Angular, Web APIs)

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China Courses toward Masters in Enterprise Management

September 2019 - May 2020

Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan

Bachelors in Asian Studies with a concentration in Chinese

August 2012 - May 2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- Angular
- Node.JS

- Git/GitHub
- TypeScript
- SQL
- TDD

- Web APIs
- Scrum/Agile
- UI/UX

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

English Language Teacher

August 2018 – January 2020

Huazhong University of Science and Technology - Wuhan, China

- Outcomes: Over 150 students improved their confidence to speak publicly in English by role-playing every-day scenarios, open forum discussions of current events, and creative expression through skits and topical presentations.
- Responsibilities: Mentored students, in groups of 30+ and one-on-one, through lectures and activities centered around English to improve confidence and language capabilities.

Foreman

February 2017 – July 2018

Down to Earth Lawn Service - Oak Park, Michigan

- Outcomes 150+ repeat customers continue to sign up every year for various landscape services throughout the Spring, Autumn, and Summer seasons.
- Responsibilities Guided lawn crews in servicing weekly maintenance to over 130 residential customers' lawns and dozens of commercial properties, as well as occasionally implementing other landscape designs tailored to customer desires.